<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-22T05:27:38+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Carter Binarao</title><subtitle>A blog for what I do most in my spare time...</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Spicy Noodles Challege!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Spicy-noodles-challenge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spicy Noodles Challege!" /><published>2017-10-24T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-10-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Spicy-noodles-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Spicy-noodles-challenge/">&lt;p&gt;A little note to all, I really love spicy foods.  So when my officemates decided to have a spicy noodles challenge, I instantly said &lt;em&gt;“Game on!”&lt;/em&gt;.  We scheduled it during the visit of one of our US colleague from Utah Office who also loves spicy foods. And decided that we video record our challenge, for documentary purposes. ^_^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us haven’t tried the noodles were about to eat.  And it was trending the interwebs about eating that spicy noodles.  The instant spicy noodles are called Samyang 2x Spicy, it’s the one with the red plastic.  I think this instant noodle comes from Korea, because they also love spicy foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, watch the video below for our Samyang Spicy Noodles Challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;social-links&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UMsH6Ck7P6U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A little note to all, I really love spicy foods. So when my officemates decided to have a spicy noodles challenge, I instantly said “Game on!”. We scheduled it during the visit of one of our US colleague from Utah Office who also loves spicy foods. And decided that we video record our challenge, for documentary purposes. ^_^</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Christmas is here!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Christmas-is-here/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christmas is here!" /><published>2016-12-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Christmas-is-here</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Christmas-is-here/">&lt;p&gt;As the song by Andy Williams entitled &lt;em&gt;It’s the most wonderful time of the year&lt;/em&gt;.  Yup, Christmas is here, the joyful and wonderful season of the year.  You can see, feel and hear it in every corner in our town.  Some started decorating or playing Christmas songs as early as September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the time when children or choir groups sing joyful carols in their neighbor’s house.  For some, it’s the best time for family reunions or friends that are separated for a long time and meet again during this season to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also the time for the owners of shopping malls to make a Christmas sale on their products.  The stores/malls are full with shoppers buying gifts for their parents, sons, daughters, god-childrens and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the only holiday or season that I or maybe you feel in every person you’ve met are jolly and the hearts shining.  It is really indeed the most wonderful time of the year.  All I can hope is that every day is Christmas day where everyone is always sharing and laughing and having a good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To you who is reading this, I wish you a very Merry Christmas, may you and your family will be blessed with good health, happiness and good fortune today and the days to come.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As the song by Andy Williams entitled It’s the most wonderful time of the year. Yup, Christmas is here, the joyful and wonderful season of the year. You can see, feel and hear it in every corner in our town. Some started decorating or playing Christmas songs as early as September.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When should we start investing?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/When-should-we-start-investing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When should we start investing?" /><published>2015-10-09T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-10-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/When-should-we-start-investing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/When-should-we-start-investing/">&lt;p&gt;Well, I don’t think there is an exact or perfect age to start investing.  Even when we are children we’ve started investing in ourselves by studying in schools.  We are never too young or old to start investing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investing is, in many ways, like learning a second language.  It’s easier and more rewarding if we started when we’re young.  Like when I used to save coins in my piggy bank at the start of the year and collect it by the end of the year.  I’ve been fascinated with the concept of storing something away with the hope that its value will grow over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that a good time to begin investing is when you start your first “real” job.  Like a job that supports you and your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could start investing by taking care of our immediate cash needs.  Most financial books or experts suggest saving an emergency fund of three to six months’ worth of expenses before anything long-term that we wouldn’t want to have to cash in unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started late in financial investing because no one gives an advice on how to manage my finances.  When we’re young we really don’t care where most of our money goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If our emergency fund and retirement fund are taken care of and still have extra money to invest.  Then we could start small amounts like 2 to 5 percents of our monthly income.  So if you’re reading this, give it a thought and start planning on investing your extra money to make it double or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start slow and spend a lot of time learning, and you could find investing an interesting and profitable hobby–or perhaps a career path.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Well, I don’t think there is an exact or perfect age to start investing. Even when we are children we’ve started investing in ourselves by studying in schools. We are never too young or old to start investing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Visit to HongKong Disneyland</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/My-Visit-to-HongKong-Disneyland/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Visit to HongKong Disneyland" /><published>2015-09-06T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-09-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/My%20Visit%20to%20HongKong%20Disneyland</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/My-Visit-to-HongKong-Disneyland/">&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5688/30538996573_2269a00f53_n.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumbNail img-post&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;213&quot; alt=&quot;Hong Kong Disneyland&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friends and I decided to have a trip to HongKong.  This country offers lots of delicious foods, amazing places, and amazing amusement parks.  One of which I didn’t let pass is to visit Disneyland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn’t watch all the theater shows, ride all the rides available even spending the entire day there.  There are lots of scheduled shows that time one of which we watched is the Lion King and it was fantastically amazing.  We’ve ridden lots of the rides there and one of my favorites is the Space Mountain.  It’s a roller coaster with a basic wild mouse coaster in the dark.  It will give you a walk through the spaceport, the blast-off into space, the on-ride music, the ride through the star field.  It’s made me wow and enjoy every bit of the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of stores inside the park, which offers everything you could imagine of course with a Disneyland image on it.  From simple keychains to pillows, shirts, bags, hats, Disney character figurines, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended the day in HongKong Disneyland with a parade of some famous Disney characters and a 30 minutes’ wonderful fireworks display in the famous Disney castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience while you’re there is simply amazingly magical.  I was like a kid again enjoying everything I see.  It’s worth to visit Disneyland while you are in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My friends and I decided to have a trip to HongKong. This country offers lots of delicious foods, amazing places, and amazing amusement parks. One of which I didn’t let pass is to visit Disneyland.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lets go Kayak!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Lets-go-kayak/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lets go Kayak!" /><published>2015-05-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-05-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Lets-go-kayak</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Lets-go-kayak/">&lt;p&gt;During my summer escapade with friends in the beautiful town of Badian, south of Cebu.  I have experienced Kayaking, even though the sun is hot, it didn’t stop me and my friends enjoy the beach and kayaking through the beach.  We kayak from one beach shore to the other, I estimated it a 2 or 3 kilometers away from each other.  It was fun and the pain of the muscles brought by rowing was worth it when we reach the other beach.  It has a nice white sand and clear sea water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took this photo using my Canon 60D with the settings focal length to 17mm, shutter speed at 1/50 sec, Aperture at f22 and ISO 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7778/17716496462_5d17d6e3ca_n.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumbNail img-post&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">During my summer escapade with friends in the beautiful town of Badian, south of Cebu. I have experienced Kayaking, even though the sun is hot, it didn’t stop me and my friends enjoy the beach and kayaking through the beach. We kayak from one beach shore to the other, I estimated it a 2 or 3 kilometers away from each other. It was fun and the pain of the muscles brought by rowing was worth it when we reach the other beach. It has a nice white sand and clear sea water.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I see you</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/I-see-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I see you" /><published>2015-05-09T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/I-see-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/I-see-you/">&lt;p&gt;During my visit to Davao City, south of the 	Philippines, I got a chance of visiting an interesting farm, the Davao Crocodile Park, the city’s answer to a “zoo”.  This recreational park is home to a variety of animals, it even has a tiger.  I took a shot of this Ostrich while they are keeping cool under a tree against the heat of the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be posting some of my photo’s of the beautiful creatures I’ve took during my visit at the Crocodile Park.  Hopefully I can return there again and enjoy seeing the wonderful creatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7667/17529126399_6be5e5f78b_n.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumbNail img-post&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">During my visit to Davao City, south of the Philippines, I got a chance of visiting an interesting farm, the Davao Crocodile Park, the city’s answer to a “zoo”. This recreational park is home to a variety of animals, it even has a tiger. I took a shot of this Ostrich while they are keeping cool under a tree against the heat of the sun.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sunset by the beach</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Sunset-by-the-beach/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sunset by the beach" /><published>2015-05-07T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-05-07T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Sunset-by-the-beach</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Sunset-by-the-beach/">&lt;p&gt;I have a chance to shoot a sunset by the beach during my last vacation.  I grab my tripod and camera to setup a sunset shot.  It was nice because it is low tide and I have a rock as a foreground for my sunset shot.  I set my camera settings to ISO 100, the aperture to f16, with the lens set to a 35mm wide and tried multiple shots with 1sec to 5secs shutter speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result was perfectly fine and I love it.  Hoping to shoot more sunsets in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8684/17195162047_fa2a716498_n.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumbNail img-post&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I have a chance to shoot a sunset by the beach during my last vacation. I grab my tripod and camera to setup a sunset shot. It was nice because it is low tide and I have a rock as a foreground for my sunset shot. I set my camera settings to ISO 100, the aperture to f16, with the lens set to a 35mm wide and tried multiple shots with 1sec to 5secs shutter speed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bahay Kubo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Bahay-Kubo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bahay Kubo" /><published>2015-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Bahay-Kubo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Bahay-Kubo/">&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7763/17387945682_e6e8213b57_n.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumbNail img-post&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last long weekend, my friends and I were having a summer getaway in the province of Badian, Cebu Philippines.  This photo was taken in the Terra Manna Resort where we have stayed for 3 days and 2 nights.  The summer getaway was a blast, we had so much fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One cold night, I wasn’t feeling asleep at that time so I grab my camera and was looking for a something to shoot.  As I was walking in the middle of the night, I found this cottage house that was not used, I set up my tripod and camera and compose a shot to include the coconut tree.  Notice that the leaves of the tree are blurry, it’s because of the wind.  It added a nice effect to the photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a long exposure shot with camera sets to 35mm, ISO 100 and 30 sec shutter speed and this is the result.  Just a little tweak in Lightroom to adjust the white balance and the colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the result and enjoyed looking for something to shoot in the cold silent night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you like it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last long weekend, my friends and I were having a summer getaway in the province of Badian, Cebu Philippines. This photo was taken in the Terra Manna Resort where we have stayed for 3 days and 2 nights. The summer getaway was a blast, we had so much fun.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To infinity and beyond</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/To-infinity-and-beyond/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To infinity and beyond" /><published>2015-04-18T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-04-18T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/To-infinity-and-beyond</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/To-infinity-and-beyond/">&lt;p&gt;That is my boss, during our summer party last April 18, 2015 on our way to the Pandanon Island of Bohol, Philippines.  In the mid-way of our trip he choose to sit in the front edge of the boat that we are riding.  So I grab my camera and took the shot of him with the nice sea view heading to the island.  It looks a little scary but only at first, you’ll get a hang of it when you’ve tried it.  We’ll YOLO (you only live once), so take a chance to try new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shot was capture using a Tamron SP AF 17-50mm and Canon 60D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7676/17054315697_093dd1a986_n.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumbNail img-post&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">That is my boss, during our summer party last April 18, 2015 on our way to the Pandanon Island of Bohol, Philippines. In the mid-way of our trip he choose to sit in the front edge of the boat that we are riding. So I grab my camera and took the shot of him with the nice sea view heading to the island. It looks a little scary but only at first, you’ll get a hang of it when you’ve tried it. We’ll YOLO (you only live once), so take a chance to try new things.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wedding Rings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Wedding-Rings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wedding Rings" /><published>2015-04-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Wedding-Rings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Wedding-Rings/">&lt;p&gt;This photo was taken using a Canon EF 50mm II Lens.  The area where the groom, the bride and the entourage was preparing before the event has a little bit of space to shoot.  So I was looking for a better place where to shoot the wedding rings of the couple.  Preparing for the shot, we use a glass table with a yellow light underneath it to get the warmth and gold effect.  And also use the brides bouquet of flowers as background for the rings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have set my camera settings to f1.8, ISO 125 with a 1/125 shutter speed.  I am happy with what the result of this shot, the nifty fifty lens of Canon saves my life here given with a tight space during the photoshoot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7667/16918102629_2121fab970_n.jpg&quot; class=&quot;thumbNail img-post&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This photo was taken using a Canon EF 50mm II Lens. The area where the groom, the bride and the entourage was preparing before the event has a little bit of space to shoot. So I was looking for a better place where to shoot the wedding rings of the couple. Preparing for the shot, we use a glass table with a yellow light underneath it to get the warmth and gold effect. And also use the brides bouquet of flowers as background for the rings.</summary></entry></feed>